[Music]
[音樂]
little fox Journey to the West chapter 1 the
小狐狸西遊記第一章
[Music]
[音樂]
monkey from the beginning of time a rock had sat high on top of a mountain M the Sun the moon Heaven and Earth all worked
猴子從一開始就有一塊石頭高高地坐在山頂上M太陽月亮天地都能運作
their magic on the Rock one day the rock split
他們在巖石上的魔法有一天巖石裂開了
open inside was a monkey the monkey stood up and
打開裏面是一只猴子猴子站起來
stretched suddenly powerful light shot from his eyes
突然從他的眼睛裏射出強大的光
for a moment the light reached the cloud Palace in heaven the Jade Emperor ruler of Heaven
光到達天上的雲宮玉帝天上的主宰
sat up he turned to one of his captains who was standing nearby find out what caused that light
坐起來，他轉向站在附近的一名船長，找出是什麼原因導致那盞燈
said the emperor yes your majesty said the captain the captain rushed out of the
說皇帝是的陛下說船長船長衝出
hall he looked out the southern Gate of Heaven and saw the monkey on earth below the light was gone but the captain had
他望向南方的天堂之門看到地球上的猴子在燈光下消失了但船長
magical sight he could see everything that had just happened interesting said the
神奇的景象他可以看到剛剛發生的一切有趣的事情說
captain well said the Jade emperor when the captain returned what caused the
隊長說得好玉皇大帝當隊長回來時
light it was a monkey said the captain a monkey asked the Jade Emperor yes said
輕一隻猴子說船長一隻猴子問玉皇帝是說
the captain he's on the fruit and flower Mountain down on Earth there had been a rock on the
隊長他在水果和花朵上地球上的山上有一塊巖石
mountain the monkey came from the rock the light Shone from the monkey's
山猴子來自巖石的光芒從猴子的
eyes the emperor thought for a moment and then Shrugged I'm not surprised he
皇帝想了一會然後聳聳肩我並不驚訝他
said amazing things happen when heaven and earth work together
說當天地一起工作時會發生驚人的事情
[Music]
【音樂】
As Time passed monkey learned to walk run and climb he drank from streams and ate
隨著時間的流逝猴子學會走路跑步和攀爬他從溪流中喝水吃東西
grasses and leaves he gathered fruit and explored caves and
草和葉子他採集水果探索洞穴
[Music]
【音樂】
mountaintops he became friends with all the other monkeys and apes
他和所有其他猴子和猿類成為朋友
[Music]
【音樂】
at night he slept under a cliff one very hot morning all the monkeys and apes were playing in the
在一個非常炎熱的早晨他睡在懸崖下所有的猴子和猿猴
shade it is so hot today cried one monkey let's play in the
的陰影今天太熱了一隻猴子喊道讓我們玩
Stream good idea said another monkey the monkeys and apes ran to the stream the
串流好主意說另一隻猴子猴子和猿猴跑向小溪
water rolled and bounced over the Rocks the monkey jumped into the cool
水在巖石上翻滾反彈猴子跳進涼爽的
water everyone splashed and played after a few minutes one monkey scratched her
水大家濺水玩了幾分鐘後一隻猴子抓傷了她
head we all love this stream she said we drink from it we swim in it we
我們都喜歡這條小溪她說我們喝水遊泳
know that it flows all the way to the ocean but does anyone know where the stream begins they all looked at one another
知道它一路流向大海但有沒有人知道小溪的起點
and shook their heads we have not nothing to do today the monkey continued why don't we follow
搖了搖頭我們今天沒什麼可做的猴子繼續為什麼我們不跟著
the stream to find its source that sounds like fun said another monkey let's go said a third monkey
找到它的來源聽起來很有趣另一隻猴子說我們走吧第三隻猴子說
everyone jumped out of the water they ran alongside the stream and swung from tree to tree they jumped over rocks and
每個人都跳出他們沿著溪流奔跑的水面從一棵樹搖擺到另一棵樹跳過巖石
climbed up steep Cliffs higher and higher they went up the mountain until they reached an enormous waterfall
爬上陡峭的懸崖越來越高他們爬上山直到到達一個巨大的瀑布
Mist filled the air the water crashed down roaring like thunder I wonder what's behind that
霧充滿了空氣水像雷聲般轟轟烈烈地沖下來我想知道背後是什麼
waterfall said one monkey me too said a second monkey but nobody could jump
瀑布說一隻猴子我也說第二隻猴子但沒有人能跳
through it whoever can jump through and come back alive will be our King said A gibon is anyone brave enough to try all
通過它誰能跳過來活著回來就會是我們的國王說吉本是任何勇於嘗試的人
the monkeys and apes looked at one another they shook their
猴子和猿猴互相看了看
heads I'm not going to try said a tall monkey me neither said a short monkey a
頭我不會說一隻高大的猴子我也不說一隻矮小的猴子
voice called out I'll do it everyone moved out of the way as the speaker stepped forward it was
聲音說我會做每個人都走開當演講者向前走的時候
monkey are you sure asked the Gibbon it looks dangerous monkey laughed I'm not afraid of anything and
猴子你肯定問長臂猿它看起來很危險猴子笑我什麼都不怕
when when I come back I will be king monkey took a deep breath and leaped into the
當我回來的時候我會成爲猴王深吸一口氣
[Music]
【音樂】
waterfall Journey to the West chapter 2 the waterfall
瀑布西遊第二章瀑布
[Music]
【音樂】
cave monkeys splashed through the waterfall and landed in a large cave
洞穴猴子濺過瀑布降落在一個大洞穴
his eyes opened wide the cave was filled with bamboo trees and beautiful
他的眼睛睜得大大的洞穴充滿了竹樹美麗
flowers moss covered the walls a stream flowed through the cave
花苔覆蓋了穿過洞穴的溪流
and glowing light and Mist filled the air monkey found a long table with bowls
發光的光和霧充滿了空氣猴子發現了一張放著碗的長桌
cups and plates a fireplace sat against one wall deeper in the cave monkey found
仰臥起盤壁爐靠在洞穴猴深處的一面牆上
bedrooms with cozy beds outside the other monkeys and apes were looking at the waterfall do you think he made it
臥室其他猴子和猿猴外面有舒適的牀看著瀑布你覺得他成功了嗎
through asked one monkey no said another monkey he probably got washed away down the
問一隻猴子沒有說另一隻他可能被沖走的猴子
river suddenly Splash monkey shot out of the waterfall and landed in front of the
駕駛者突然從瀑布中射出水花猴落在
group you're alive said to monkey monkey laughed yes and we are very lucky I
一組你還活著說猴子猴子笑了是的我們很幸運我
found a perfect home for all of us follow me Monkey Jumped back through the
為我們所有人找到一個完美的家跟著我猴子跳回去
water some of the monkeys scratched their heads it still looks dangerous said one
一些猴子抓頭看起來仍然很危險
monkey let's go said the Gibbon he leaped through the waterfall after that Another Monkey
猴子我們說長臂猿跳過瀑布之後另一隻猴子
Jumped through then some more jumped soon all of the monkeys and apes
跳過然後很快就跳過了所有的猴子和猿類
were in the cave everyone ran around to see all the wonderful things this cave is beautiful said the
每個人在洞穴裡跑來跑去看這個洞穴美麗的美好事物
given some of the monkeys and apes began fighting and arguing they grabbed plates and bowls
一些猴子和猿開始打架爭論他們抓住盤子和碗
from one another others fought over the bedrooms oh I saw this bed first yelled
彼此爭奪臥室哦我看到這張牀第一次大喊大叫
one monkey no yelled Another Monkey I did Monkey watched his friends for a
1猴子沒有大喊大叫我做的另一只猴子猴子看着他的朋友
moment and then folded his arms he called all the monkeys and apes
鐘然後雙臂交叉他叫所有的猴子和猿猴
stopped what they were doing they looked at Monkey I found this cave for us said
停止他們在做什麼他們看著猴子我發現這個洞穴對我們說
monkey that means I am now your king why aren't you bowing to me he's right said
這意味著我現在是你的國王你為什麼不向我鞠躬他說得對
the Gibbon he bowed to monkey and said all hail the Monkey King everyone else bowed
吉本向猴子鞠躬說所有人都向猴王鞠躬
too H The Monkey King they
H猴王他們
[Music]
【音樂】
shouted many years went by during the day the monkeys and apes played in the forest and the stream and every night
白天猴子和猿猴在森林和溪流中玩耍，每天晚上
they slept safely in their cave one night the monkeys and apes had a huge feast
有一天晚上猴子和猿猴安全地睡在洞穴裡
fruits and nuts covered the table monkeys and apes danced and sang while music played monkey sat on his throne
水果和堅果覆蓋了桌子猴子和猿猴跳舞唱歌而音樂播放猴子坐在他的寶座上
and smiled but then his smile faded soon he was frowning the Gibbon saw monkey
然後微笑但他的微笑很快就消失了他皺著眉頭對著長臂猿鋸猴
and rushed over your majesty said the Gibbon you look sad what's
衝過陛下說長臂猿你看起來很難過
wrong monkey side our life here is perfect yes that's true said the Gibbon
猴子這邊我們的生活很完美是的吉本說得沒錯
so why are you sad monkey was quiet for a moment then he said someday Our Lives
所以你為什麼悲傷的猴子沉默了一會兒然後他說有一天我們的生活
will end I wish this perfect life could last forever the Gibbon's eyes lit up oh
結束我希望這完美的生活能永遠持續吉本的眼睛亮了起來
he said you want to live forever I do said monkey the Gibbon rubbed his
她說你想永生我說猴子長臂猿揉了揉他的
chin then you must study with a sage sages are very wise people they can turn themselves into
你必須和一位賢人一起學習他們是非常聰明的人他們可以把自己變成
other animals they can fly through the sky and they know how to live
其他動物可以在天空中飛翔他們知道如何生活
forever monkey smiled again where can I find a sage he asked you must find a
永遠的猴子再次微笑我在哪裡可以找到他要求的聖人你必須找到
land with people said the Gibbon that's where you'll find a sage the next morning monkey built a
人們說長臂猿第二天早上在那裡你會發現一隻鼠尾草猴建造了一個
raft and loaded food onto it he pushed the raft into the stream and jumped
他把木筏推入小溪中跳上去
on as the raft began to float away monkey waved to his friends don't worry he called after I
當木筏開始漂走時猴子向他的朋友揮手別擔心他在我
learn how to live forever I will
學習如何永生我會
[Music]
【音樂】
return Journey to the West chapter 3 sabod
返程西遊第三章sabod
monkey sailed over the ocean for a long time finally he arrived at a new
猴子在海上航行了很長一段時間終於到達一個新的
land he walked for many years visiting towns and meeting people but he didn't find a sage
他走了很多年去城鎮和會見人但他沒有找到聖人
anywhere eventually he came to mountains covered in thick forest he headed up a steep Mountain
最終他來到茂密森林所覆蓋的山脈上了一座陡峭的山
Trail and soon heard chopping a wood cutter was chopping firewood hello said monkey are there any
小徑很快聽到砍柴人正在砍柴你好說猴子有沒有
sages in these mountains the wood cutter dropped his axe you're a monkey he
在這些山上伐木工放下斧頭你是一隻猴子他
said and you're talking yes I am said monkey and I want to live forever do you know where I can
說你說是的我是說猴子我想永生你知道我可以在哪裡
find a sage the wood cutter scratched his head well yes he said a sage named sabot
找到一位賢人木匠刮傷了他的頭是的他說了一位名叫薩博的賢人
lives on this mountain he is very wise monkey was excited where can I find
在這座山上他很聰明猴子很興奮我可以在哪裡找到
him just follow this Trail and you will come to his home said the wood cutter thank you said
鐘沿著這條小徑走你就會來到他家說伐木工謝謝你說
[Music]
【音樂】
monkey he waved goodbye to The Woodcutter and ran up the trail soon he saw a temple built into the side of the
2012年分20秒猴子他向樵夫揮手告別很快他就看到一座寺廟建在
mountain saot was sitting with his students in the main room of his Temple he looked at his oldest
索特與他的學生坐在他寺廟的主房間他看著他最年長的
student please go to the door said sabod a new student is about to arrive let him in the student looked
學生請到門口說sabod一個新學生即將到達讓他在學生看
confused okay Master he said the student got up and went to the door of the
困惑好了師父說學生起身走到門口
[Music]
【音樂】
temple he looked outside hello cold monkey I'm here to see
他看着外面你好冷猴子我是來看的
sabot a moment later monkey was standing in front of the sage I want to be your student said
機械人片刻後猴子站在聖人面前我想成為你的學生說
monkey but you're just a monkey said sabot how can you be my student monkey
猴子但你只是一隻猴子說你如何能成為我的學生猴子
laughed I might be a monkey but I can walk and talk and do many other things I traveled almost 13 years to get
歡呼我可能是一隻猴子但我可以走路說話做很多其他事情我花了將近13年的時間
here here I'm sure I can be your student sabot stared at Monkey for a moment who
在這裡我相信我可以成為你的學生盯著猴子一會兒
are your parents he asked monkey scratched his head I don't
是你的父母他讓猴子抓他的頭我不
have parents he said I was born from a rock interesting said sabod you were
刮胡子的父母他說我出生在一塊有趣的巖石上說你是
probably created by Heaven and Earth you may be my student you need a name he
可能是由天地創造的你可能是我的學生你需要一個名字
thought for a moment I will call you son
我會叫你兒子
[Music]
【音樂】
Wukong for the next seven years son Wukong lived in sod's Temple the monkey
悟空接下來的七年兒子悟空住在草坪寺廟猴子
spent his days meditating listening to his teachers lessons and doing chores one day while sabot was giving a
他花了一天的時間冥想聽老師的課程做家務
lesson Wukong started to
2014年分20秒悟空開始
[Music]
【音樂】
dance sabot stood up how dare you dance while I'm teaching he
舞蹈家sabot站起來你竟敢在我教他的時候跳舞
shouted I'm sorry said Wukong but I was so happy I needed to dance sobot calmed down you're
很抱歉悟空說但我很高興我需要跳舞機械人冷靜下來
happy yes said the monkey I love learning from you Wukong you have been here a long time what would you like to
快樂是的我喜歡向你學習的猴子悟空你來這裡很久了你想要什麼
learn from me asked zbot Wukong Shrugged I don't know you tell me what I should learn
向我學問zbot悟空聳聳肩我不知道你告訴我我應該學什麼
well said sabot I can teach you how to tell the future would you like that maybe said Wukong will it make me live
說sabot我可以教你如何告訴你未來你會喜歡嗎也許說悟空會讓我活下去
forever of course not said sabot then forget it said Wukong teach me something
之前當然沒有說sabot然後忘了它說悟空教我一些東西
else H said sabot how about some magic breathing exercises will they make me live forever
H說sabot一些神奇的呼吸練習會讓我永遠活著
asked Wukong no said sabot frowning then I'm not interested said
問悟空沒有說sabot皺眉那我就沒興趣說
Wukong sabot became angry he stood up and knocked Wukong on the head three
悟空蓄意生氣他站起來把悟空的頭敲了三下
times then he left the
然後他離開了
[Music]
【音樂】
room Wukong said another student you are very rude to master the other students all agreed
房間悟空說另一個學生你很粗魯掌握其他學生都同意
Wukong however smiled none of the other students knew it but sabot had given him a secret
悟空然而笑了笑其他學生都不知道但Sabot給了他一個祕密
message little box
短信小盒子